Nathaniel Reister

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

nathaniel.reister@gmail.com Seattle, WA 98119 (646) 634-7800

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Graduated Cum Laude with a double bachelors from SUNY Brockport in 3 years, built a business immediately after a move from New York City to Seattle, managed large commercial and residential development projects while attending a coding boot camp. With the completion of a recent internship these energies and drive will be dedicated to excelling in the field of Software Development and the anifestation of life long goals.

SKILLS

Languages/Development: C#, Python, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, APIs, Node.js

Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite3

Frameworks: .NET, Django, React, Web Forms, Entity, Bootstrap4

Architectural Paradigms: Object Oriented Programming, MVC

Project Management: Agile/Scrum, Azure DevOps, Git/GitHub

IDEs Visual Studio 2019/Code, PyCharm

Non-Technical: Team Management, Client relations, public speaking, interpersonal

communications, organizational and process management,

research driven

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer Intern | Prosper IT Consulting | Portland, OR October 2020 - December 2020 C#/.NET CRM Web Application.

Skillset: C#, .NET, Razor, Entity Framework, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap 4, Agile/Scrum, Azure DevOps, Slack

Using Entity framework Code First to develop a web application with product models that were
integrated further via relational database and scaffold to provide user manipulation of database.
 Furthermore, completion of user requested changes to UI as well as locate and correct bugs.

Python/Django Web Applications

Skillset: Python, Django, HTML, CSS, Agile/Scrum, Slack

• Using Django framework development of front and back end components of a web application that collected user preferences from search and survey results then providing them suggestions.

Construction Superintendent | Belotti Mchugh Design And ConstructionServices | Seattle, WA June 2018 - Current

 Manage and supervise development of both commercial and residential projects in the greater Seattle Area. Scope of this work included but was not limited to client and government relations, project organization, procurement of labor force and materials, oversight of installation methods, responsibility as primary administrator on site, and workflow and coordination of teams.

Owner and Operator | Fern And Hammer | Seattle, WA

October 2016 - June 2018

 Organize and perform development of residential spaces. Procurement of materials, labor, and implementation of most relevant building methods. Direct client involvement typical in projects as well as continuous research in modern building methods. Performance of administrator duties including financing, permitting, business licensing and taxation, and standard administrator responsibilities.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Developer | The Tech Academy | Portland, OR Graduated December 2020 A 1000 hr+ boot camp providing a comprehensive overview of software development with courses in C#, MVC, Python, Django, JavaScript/JQuery, SQL/TSQL(MS SQL Server), HTML5, CSS3, AJAX/XML, Source Control(Git & GitHub), Agile/Scrum Methodologies, OOP, fundamentals of computer technologies.

Bachelor of Arts | SUNY College At Brockport, Brockport, NY | Double Bachelors - Graduated MAY 2015 Communications - Mass Media, Interpersonal, Public, Persuasion tactics.

Political Sciences - Law and Legal Procedure, Constitutional Law, Comparative Politics.

Noted Achievements

- Dean's List with Honors
- Graduated cum laude
- Resident Assistant
- Chief Justice in Student Government